Jhonatan Macazana

DevOps Engineer

Lima, Peru GMT-5 (+51) 989080350 jhonatan.macazana1@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/jhonatanmacazana https://aithub.com/ihonatanmacazana

Full-stack web developer for over 2 years, involved in web development and systems design with a **DevOps** culture using container orchestrators, **Docker**, ReactJS, TypeScript, JavaScript, Go, among others. Very interested in decentralized applications, IoT devices, cloud computing, and emerging technologies. Furthermore, I have worked as a Software Architect on several Peruvian startups. I consider myself a self-taught technology enthusiast, and I love trying new technologies.

EXPERIENCE

Minskylab, DevOps Engineer | Full-stack Engineer — May 2021 - Present

Software development company focused on research and innovating solutions for everyday problems.

- Contributed with a migration to a lighter infrastructure that reduced 30% budget cost by implementing a custom PaaS with Docker, Discord and GitHub.
- Reduced deploy time from 30 m to 3 minutes by using CICD pipelines with Docker and GitHub Actions.
- Minimized overall calculation time of a large dataset by 60% by implementing a docker-based application to perform tasks on distributed systems.

Tech Stack: ReactJS, NextJS, Typescript, JavaScript, Go, Python, Docker, Terraform, Ansible, GitHub Actions.

Freelance, Software Architect — August 2020 - October 2021

Worked on more than 10 projects from telecommunication, construction, and medical companies.

- Improved the development-release workflow of a startup by 60% by setting up automated build deployments with CICD pipelines with GitHub Actions or Circle CI.
- Redesigned a router infrastructure migration with Python, speeding up the process by over 200%.

Tech Stack: Docker, Docker Swarm, Grafana, Terraform, Ansible, GitHub Actions, ReactJS, Python.

Empresa Siderurgica del Peru S.A.A., Full Stack Trainee — January 2020 - July 2020

Peruvian steel company working over 60 years with innovative practices, inherited from Gerdau, a Brazilian steel company.

- Improved SAP work orders distribution that allowed 1 in 5 workers to have a faster and easier way to check important documents by building a custom Telegram sender application with NodeJS and ReactJS.
- Removed a communication problem between technicians and administrative personnel by developing a web
 application that allows to centralize alarms and work orders from the plant with NodeJS, Node Red, ReactJS, Nginx
 and Docker.

Tech Stack: ReactJS, JavaScript, Docker, Nginx, Express.

PROJECTS

Template generator - https://github.com/jhonatanmacazana/vsr-new - 2021

CLI-tool for instantiating a specific type of project with a custom name, currently focused on frontend applications with ReactJS and Typescript. Improved my own workflow around 25% overall by reducing the boilerplate with starting projects.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Advanced: Typescript, JavaScript, Python, Go. Intermediate: SQL, Bash, C++.

Frameworks and Tools: *Advanced:* Docker, Docker Swarm, ReactJS, NextJS, GraphQL, PostgreSQL, GitHub Actions, web sockets. *Intermediate:* Flask, Django, MySQL, Terraform, Ansible.

Languages: English, fluent; Spanish, native.

EDUCATION

Universidad de Ingenieria y Tecnologia – Lima, Peru

Bachelor of Electrical Engineering, May 2021